[Music]
Hello and thank you for joining and
congratulations probably because you
already sold to your local audience as
much as possible and now uh planning
expand to other markets.
Markets is actually interesting word.
This is the one which is used in Shopify
to define localized uh shopping
experience. Yeah. such as uh languages,
maybe domains, maybe pricing. Oh, did I
say pricing? Because this is exactly
what we're going to talk about in this
session. But first, some uh rehearsal
about how Shopify do the does the
things. Let's start by looking in the
Shopify admin at some product. So this
is Berlin Berlin guest chair yellow and
I defined price right in the product
card and I can see it right in my store.
So you can see yellow chair 100 and if
you sell internationally that might be a
fine approach especially if you happen
to be in Europe and sell different
prices in euro then multiple countries
will you see the same prices but what if
your target audience is in another
country and there are different currency
let's try to sell something in Canada
you have noticed that price is updated
now it's Canadian dollars and price is
141 on. All right. How did it happen?
Here you can see that I created a new
market uh called Canada which represents
region. You can see which specific
countries it includes. Canada. And the
only thing I modified here is how to
handle currencies.
So now currency will be Canadian dollar
instead of US dollar. Yeah. And then we
can define if we want to Shopify choose
exchange rate they monitor how to how to
adjust it's so dynamic or we can put the
manual one and also we can decide here
if you want to use rounding or not much
flexibility it's up to Shopify to define
these ones uh but you can agree to it or
not all right so that's how it works
also uh pretty simple uh configure it
once and forget and uh like low effort.
So the only prices you need to maintain
will be in the uh Shopify product card.
But what if you want more advanced
scenarios in markets?
We can define actually even hierarchy of
markets. I can see that I defined Europe
as a whole Europe but also I have a
Germany where prices might be different
for some or all products. Let's take a
look. We will start with a store in the
US where we can see the Paris gas chair
which has three variants and has some
prices. Apparently prices are different
if you select different variants. So
blue one will become 200 and the green
one is the most expensive is this $300
US. Now let's move to France which is in
located in Europe. So it uses a European
market which we configured and let's see
what will happen. France Euro bonjour.
Now we are in France and we still
selling Paris chair. Black version cost
90, blue version 170, and green one 260.
Everything in euros. All right. What
about Germany?
Germany.
All right. In Germany, the black version
cost the same €9, but blue and green
difference. Something is more expensive.
Something is a little bit cheaper. Both
of them now are 200s. It's a market
specific and I want to be able to
control it. Yeah. How do I do that? In
Shopify in the new markets, you can see
the whole list of markets for regions
and we can see Europe
and uh Germany inside Europe. And if you
open it, you can see that I have a
specific catalog Paris chairs Europe.
And what about Germany?
I have another catalog which is called
Germany. If you go to the list of
catalogics, we can find it. For example,
Germany
and you can see that it's assigned to
the market and I have prices three
variants which are defined here. So that
was introduction on Shopify site. We of
course very much curious how it will
work together with a business central.
Let's explore. This is Shopify shop cart
and you can see I'm missing Shopify
admin URL and of course I love this
feature so I tend to demo it like every
season. I just copied the URL from the
Shopify admin
and let Shopify connector to transform
it into what URL I need. That's like I
use it like every time. Let's activate
it
and go to the new page which is now
called market catalog. If we go here,
it's empty, we press the button get
market catalog, which looks very
familiar to people who already using B2B
functionality of Shopify. All right, I
imported three catalogs. They are linked
to some markets. All right, you can see
that two catalogs actually in different
currency. My business central here is in
uh it's US version. So the local
currency is US dollar. So that's why
currency code is blank for local ones
and this catal is also in local currency
but uh Europe and Germany in euros and I
have my uh currencies here
by the way you can see the market name
on the right one
the same catalog actually can be linked
to multiple markets
all right I did some preparation I
prepared customer price group and they
are called Europe
and Germany Okay. And now activating
toggles here. And now we press sync
prices. What will happen? I try to keep
prices very similar to existing ones.
But for European ones, I increase it by
one and German by two and in one case by
three. So it will be like more
noticeable to see if update has happened
or not. All right. seen prices uh
completed. Let's go back to online store
and we are in German version and you can
see that price is 102 two as I promised
I will increase something 2002
and 2003 just to demonstrate that
something is changing when I click these
buttons. All right. Now, let's explore
French version.
And you can see price is 91,
171, and 261
increased by one. As promised, just to
illustrate that synchronization indeed
operates as expected. All right, as we
are here in the list of markets, let's
explore a little bit further. We talk
about regions but you can see the folder
which is called POS
point of sale. So technically you can
define market for point of sale. You can
press this button and specify for which
point of sales you want to define
prices. And you can see that I have
several but I picked only main location
because my main location is in the right
currency. So there is also possibility
to define by regions. But it doesn't
makes much sense for POS. It should be
only in local country. But what else we
can do? We can create try to create a
new market and see what it is possible
to define. So you can define it for
regions
POS location or company locations. That
is actually only available for B for
plus customers who are using B2B. So now
you have two options how to define uh
prices for B2B customers. Either via
market, you can define market locations
uh company locations
and select all locations here or you can
actually open specific
specific B2B customer and add catalogic
from here. I don't have a non assigned
catalog that's why list is is empty. So
two options
up to you which one you want to uh use
in uh in Shopify because in business
central in Shopify connector we support
both. So if you defined market with a
company locations it will land it here
in Shopify market catalog because
catalog linked to market but if you
decided to link catalog to company
directly then you can find it into in
the B2B catalics we slightly changed
names. It before it was just Catal now
it is B2B catalics. So here you will see
only catalogs which are linked to B2B
customers directly. It works uh the same
way as before. Plus, you can see the new
currency code field. So, now Catalak may
have a currency.
All right.
Thank you for watching. Check the
description. There are some useful
links. Bye.